If a voiceless stop is in a word-initial position, then
	the voiceless stop is aspirated

If a voiceless stop is preceded by s, then
	the voiceless stop is unaspirated

If a sonorant is preceded by a word-initial voiceless stop, then
	the sonorant is devoiced

If a voiced plosive is adjacent to a voiceless segment, then
	the voiced plosive is devoiced

If a sonorant is preceded by a glottal stop, then
	the sonorant is produced with creaky voice

If h is at the beginning of a stressed syllable, then
	h is produced with breathy voice

If h is at the beginning of an unstressed syllable, then
	h is deleted

If a stop precedes another consonant, then
	the stop is produced without audible release

If n precedes a consonant, then
	n assimilates its place of articulation

If m precedes f, then
	m becomes labiodental

If t precedes th, then
	t becomes dental

If d precedes th, then
	d becomes dental

If t precedes r, then
	t becomes post-alveolar

If d precedes r, then
	then d becomes post-alveolar

If t precedes a nasal, then
	t becomes ʔ

If an alveolar precedes j, then
	the alveolar becomes a postalveolar

If t is between two vowels, then
	t becomes ɾ

If d is between two vowels, then
	d becomes ɾ

If l is in word end position or at the end of a syllable, then
	l becomes velarized

If there is a sequence of three consonants and none of them is r, then
	the second consonant is deleted

If a vowel precedes a nasal, then
	the vowel is nasalized

If a vowel is tense, then
	the vowel is diphthongized

If a vowel is in an open syllable, then
	the vowel is lengthened

If a vowel precedes a voiced consonant, then
	the vowel is lengthened

If schwa precedes a sonorant, then
	schwa is deleted


 